endocrine.org 2019-11-26

# Privacy Policy | Hormone Health Network

### Privacy Statement

The Endocrine Society respects the privacy of our users and created this privacy statement to apprise you of our information gathering and dissemination practices. We reserve the right to modify this statement at any time, so please check back periodically for our latest privacy practices.

This Privacy Statement includes, without limitation, the following information:

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected from you through the website;
  * How such information is used;
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information;
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in your information, and
  * What security obligations are in place.

### Collection of Information

Personal identifying information is your name, street or email address, phone number or any other information when used by itself or with other data, might identify you individually. The Endocrine Society does not collect this information on this website except where it is sent to us voluntarily. For example, when you order goods or services online, we ask you for personal identifying information so we can fulfill those goods and services or contact you.

### Use of Information

The Endocrine Society may use the personal identifying information we collect to contact you in the future. Specifically, we may send promotional emails notifying you of events, products and services, significant developments, or other information we believe might be of interest. We will not disclose your email address to third parties.

Once someone voluntarily provides an email address, the Endocrine Society uses that information to email the person for transaction follow-up, promotions and communications. We collect data to track the effectiveness of emails, which enables us to better serve our varied audiences.

The Endocrine Society does not rent email addresses or phone numbers to third parties. However, we do rent the names and mailing addresses we gather to third parties. These third parties may subsequently contact you by mail.

### Choices

All Endocrine Society's marketing emails include a link for unsubscribing. If you do not wish to have your personal identifying information used or disclosed for these purposes, you may "opt-out." By logging into your account on endocrine.org, you can “opt-out” or unsubscribe to email messages. We will apply any unsubscribe request as quickly as possible. However, because email campaigns may already be in progress, some email messages may still be sent until the opt-out request can be fully processed. Once the opt-out is processed that email address will no longer receive marketing or promotional emails from Endocrine Society. Email addresses are still used in support of specific transactions (e.g., membership renewal notices, order confirmations)

If you do not have an Endocrine Society account, please contact us at [info@endocrine.org](mailto:info@endocrine.org). In your email, please indicate one of the following opt-out choices:

  * NO OUTSIDE DISTRIBUTION (please do not disclose my name or address on a commercial mailing list)
  * NO EMAIL (please do not include me in lists for Society email correspondence)
  * NO MAIL (please do not include me on any internal promotional Endocrine Society mailings or on any commercial mailing lists)

**European Union Residents Only**

If you are a European Union resident and wish to have your personal information removed from our systems entirely and permanently, please contact us at [info@endocrine.org](mailto:info@endocrine.org) to initiate the process. Please keep in mind this is irreversible and we will not be able to recover your previous membership terms or any other past records if you wish to rejoin or become customer in the future.

Notwithstanding any of the above, we may release membership lists or personal identifying information if we determine the release is appropriate to comply with the law, to enforce or apply our contractual rights or obligations, to protect the rights, property, or safety of the Endocrine Society, our members, or others, or to establish a legal claim or defense.

**Non-Personal Information**

To serve our members and website visitors better, the Endocrine Society tracks and analyzes the traffic to our website. We may collect information about your computer and the sections of our website visited. For example, we may collect IP Addresses and use information on the types of computer or web browser you use. This information is used in the aggregate to create statistics for our site and for our system administration. It enables us to analyze the use of our website and design it to better reflect our users' interests.

In addition, we may place so-called "cookies" on the computers of visitors. This will enable you to return to our website and use its services without logging in and identifying yourself each time. We do not use the cookies to track your activities other than on our website.

**  
Continuing Medical Education (CME) and Maintenance of Certification (MOC)**

The Endocrine Society records learner's personal information as provided on CME evaluations to allow for issuance and tracking of CME certificates. The Endocrine Society may also track aggregate responses to questions in activities and evaluations and use these data to inform the ongoing evaluation and improvement of its CME program. No individual performance data or any other personal information collected from evaluations is shared with third parties.

### Correction of Information

If you wish to review the information we have collected from you (e.g., to confirm we have the correct address), please visit the [My Account](https://ams.endocrine.org/eweb/DynamicPage.aspx?webcode=FullIndInfo&Site=ES) section on our website or contact us at [info@endocrine.org](mailto:info@endocrine.org). We will respond to you promptly and provide you with opportunity to correct any errors.

### Security

The Endocrine Society has significant protections in place to ensure the privacy of your personal information. Our membership database and connected systems are implemented and designed to protect your information. We collect the minimum information necessary to fulfill our goods and services, such as becoming a member, purchasing a product, or registering for a course or event. Multiple layers of physical, administrative, and electronic protections have been put in place to protect all information from unauthorized use, access, or malicious activity. Personnel procedures and processes have been developed and are in place with an emphasis on privacy. Our systems are audited by independent third parties. Effective customer privacy and security are a top priority for our organization. While we have safeguards in place to prevent interception or unauthorized access, there is no absolute guarantee of security. In the unlikely event of a security breach resulting in the disclosure of non-public personal information of end users, Endocrine Society will promptly investigate the matter and notify end users within 72 hours of becoming aware of the breach. We do not represent, warrant, or guarantee your personal information will be protected against unauthorized access, loss, misuse, or alterations, and do not accept any liability for the security of the personal information submitted to us or for your or third parties' use or misuse of personal information.

### DMD Healthcare Communications Network℠ Privacy Statement

This digital service participates in the DMD Healthcare Communication Network℠ (the "Network"), and as such has implemented various technologies for universal registration/login among all Network member websites. These technologies are managed by DMD Marketing Corp. ("DMD"), and may involve the collection, receipt, and sharing of information with DMD, its clients and other Network members. If you would like to understand how this digital service’s participation in the Network affects your privacy, please click here: <http://usersupport.dmdconnects.com/PrivacyPolicy.htm>

Please note that the Network registration/login system may be different from the registration/login used by this digital service for other products and services. To the extent that anything in this privacy policy conflicts with the policy for the Network technologies, the conflict will be resolved in favor of the policy applicable to the Network technologies.
